Guide to the Phyllis Chesler Papers, 1968-2003 RL.00221
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings Series, 1969-1988 and undated
  - Sacred Bond subseries, 1986-1988
    - Drafts, 1987-1988 (Box W40)
      - Typescripts - Miscellaneous (Box W41)
      - Typescripts - Miscellaneous (Box W41)
    - Committee for Mary Beth Whitehead, 1987
      The Committee for Mary Beth Whitehead was founded by Chesler during the "Baby M" trial as an agency to support the rights of Mary Beth Whitehead, "Baby M's" birth mother. The papers in this section chiefly document the administrative activities of this organization. The folders are arranged alphabetically.
      - CMBW Stationary (Box W41)
      - Daily Planner, 1987, June (Box W41)
      - Expenses-Baby M. (Box W41)
      - Factsheet, 1987, Feb. (Box W41)
      - Financial Materials (Box W41)
      - MBW Birthday Party, 1987, March 29 (Box W41)
      - MBW Deposits (Box W41)
      - Media and Support Contacts- Baby M Media (Box W41)
      - Press Kits, 1987 (Box W41)
      - Rally against infertility center, 1987, April 5 (Box W41)
      - Requests (Box W41)
      - Sponsored Activities, 1987 (Box W41)
      - Working File (Box W41)
      - Xeroxed Checks (Box W41)
    - Publicity, 1988
      These materials document efforts made to publicize the publication of Sacred Bond. The folders are arranged alphabetically using titles established by Chesler.
      - Book Party List for Sacred Bond, 1988, June 8 (Box W41)
      - Correspondence (Box W41)
      - CR and MMDA (Box W41)
      - Film Festival Idea for Sacred Bond (Box W41)
      - Information (Box W41)
      - Lists of Recipients of Book (Box W41)
      - Media Requests, 1988, March-April (Box W41)
      - Media on Surrogate Moms (Box W41)
      - Meeting with Sandy Brewarsky (Box W41)
      - News from Times Books press release (Box W41)
      - Quotes for Sacred Bond (Box W41)
      - Recipients of Media Kits for Sacred Bond (Box W41)
      - Revolution Books NYC, 1987, June 13 (Box W41)
      - Tentative Publicity Tours as Suggested by Ivan Held (Box W41)
      - unspecified (Box W41)
      - "We are Unfit," 3-12-87 (Box W41)
    - Interviews, 1987
      - Nancy B.: Example (Box W41)
      - Nancy B.: Surrogate Mother (Box W41)
      - Elizabeth K.: Surrogate Mom (Box W41)
      - Peter K., 1987, July 7 (Box W41)
      - Vicky W.: Related Documents and Writings (Box W41)
      - Vicky W.: Surrogate Mother (Box W41)
      - Alison W., June 2, 1987 (Box W41)
      - Laurie Y. (Box W41)
    - Audiocassettes, 1987 (Box W42)
      Audio recordings of interviews conducted by Chesler while researching Sacred Bond. Also included are recordings of general dictation and of speeches and presentations made by Chesler. Many of the tapes contain more than one interview. Audiocassette titles are taken from Chesler's labels.
      - Baby M., 1987, April 25 (Box W42)
      - Baby M. Dictation, 1987, April 28 (Box W42)
      - Nancy B., 1987, June 10 (Box W42)
      - Nancy B., continued. (Box W42)
      - Phyllis Chesler at Revolution Books, 1987, June 6 (Box W42)
      - Phyllis Chesler at Revolution Books, 1987, June 6 / Paul Byers Class at Teachers College (Box W42)
      - Elizabeth K., 1987, July 17 (Box W42)
      - PC and RD, 1987, July 9 (Box W42)
      - Rutgers, 1987, May 2 (Box W42)
      - Vicky W., undated (Box W42)
      - Vicky W., continued / Revolution Books, 1987 (Box W42)
      - Mary Beth Whitehead, 1987, June 8 / Nancy B., continued (Box W42)
  - Miscellaneous Writings subseries, ca. 1970-1980 and undated
    Miscellaneous essays, stories, and other writings with feminist themes. Arranged alphabetically using Chesler's folder titles. Most writings are undated. Miscellaneous unidentified notes, manuscript pages, and other unidentified writings are arranged at the end of this subseries.
    - Analysis of Tostoy's Anna Karenina (Box W42)
    - "The Beauty Parlor," undated (Box W42)
    - Book Suggestions (Box W42)
    - Conference on Women's Health, 1975 (Box W42)
    - Custody Book (Box W42)
    - Edited/Typed Witchcraft (Box W42)
    - Essays (Box W42)
    - "The Female Social Role and Madness: Sex-Role Stereotyping, Adjustment, and Psychiatric Symptoms" (Box W42)
    - Feminist Writing Themes (Box W42)
    - Homosexuality Story (Box W42)
    - "Marcia Blum: A Jewish Painter," undated (Box W42)
    - "Men and Women: Jealousy, Monogamy, Polygamy" (Box W42)
    - "Payo Story," undated (Box W42)
    - Play, undated (Box W42)
    - " 'Please Can You Help Me?' Letters to a Psychologist" (2 folders) (Box W42)
    - Psychiatry Magazine's Memos (Box W42)
    - Psychologist Reports/Tests, undated (Box W42)
    - Quotes (Box W42)
    - Shelved Pictures for Next Book, undated (Box W42)
    - Story Notes (Misc) (Box W42)
    - Stories (4 folders) (Box W42)
    - "Whatever Happened to Marcia?" (Box W42)
    - Witches (Box W42)
    - "Women as Psychiatric & Psychotherapeutic Patients," 1971 (Box W42)
    - "Women & 'Mental Illness'" (Box W42)
    - Wonder Woman (2 folders) (Box W42)
    - Unidentified Miscellaneous Writings (Box W42)
- Custody Speakout Project Series, 1985-1986.
  Contains organizational files including proposals, resource lists, fundraising, speaker information, and agenda files for Custody Speakout Project. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Agenda (Box CSO1)
  - Alphabetical List (Box CSO1)
  - American Psychological Association (Box CSO1)
  - American Writers (Box CSO1)
  - Arts & Science Fellowship: Community Colleges (Box CSO1)
  - Author's League Fund (Box CSO1)
  - Budget Proposals (Box CSO1)
  - Celebrities List (Box CSO1)
  - Change, Inc. (Box CSO1)
  - Child Custody (Box CSO1)
  - The Children's Foundation (Box CSO1)
  - Committee on Research Support (Box CSO1)
  - Congressional Committee (Box CSO1)
  - Contacts (Box CSO1)
  - Contacts for Publicity (Box CSO1)
  - Council for International Exchange of Scholars (Box CSO1)
  - Crisis Calls Since July 28, 1985 (Box CSO1)
  - Custody Film Budget Proposal Amethyst Foundation (Box CSO1)
  - Custody Handbook Chesler/Bartram, 1986 (Box CSO1)
  - Custody Proposal (New) (Box CSO1)
  - Essays on Child Custody, 1981-7 (Box CSO1)
  - Equal Rights for Mothers (Box CSO1)
  - Final Copy, Proposal (Box CSO1)
  - Foundation for Custody Video (Box CSO1)
  - Foundation Funding (Box CSO1)
  - Funders: Key (Box CSO1)
  - Fundraising Contracts: Individuals (Box CSO1)
  - Fundraising Letter/Speakout (Box CSO1)
  - Funding Ideas (Box CSO1)
  - Forbes (Box CSO1)
  - Ford Foundation (Box CSO1)
  - Foundation Center (Box CSO1)
  - Foundation List/Standard Letter (Box CSO1)
  - Foundations (Box CSO1)
  - Foundations - Possibilities (Box CSO1)
  - Frances Lear (Box CSO1)
  - Funders -- Key (Box CSO1)
  - Funding Ideas (Box CSO1)
  - Fundraising Budget - Sample (Box CSO1)
  - Fundraising Contacts (Box CSO1)
  - Fundraising Letters (2 folders) (Box CSO1)
  - Fundraising Letters -- Already Sent (Box CSO1)
  - Fundraising -- Mt. Sinai Medical (Box CSO1)
  - Fundraising -- Planning Resources (Box CSO1)
  - Fundraising Portfolio (Box CSO1)
  - Fundraising - "Thank You" Letters (Box CSO1)
  - Grant/Fundraising (Box CSO1)
  - Grants (Box CSO1)
  - Graphics for Speakout (Box CSO1)
  - Grassroots Fundraising Events (Box CSO1)
  - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation (Box CSO1)
  - Health Network (Box CSO1)
  - ISORS/Name Sept. 22 Mtg. (Box CSO1)
  - International Master List (Box CSO1)
  - Joint Foundation, 1983 (Box CSO1)
  - Large Funding Proposal (Box CSO1)
  - Law Conference (Box CSO1)
  - Letters for Mothers in Need 5/1 (Box CSO1)
  - Letters to Be Sent/Drafts for Phyllis to Schulman/Weitzman (Box CSO1)
  - Letters to Individuals (Box CSO1)
  - Letters to Possible Speakers (Box CSO1)
  - List of Mothers Written About, Not Interviewed (Box CSO1)
  - List of Mothers: Working Pool I've Interviewed (Box CSO1)
  - List of Potential Steering Committee (Box CSO1)
  - List of Resources/Back to the Book (Box CSO1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box CSO1)
  - Morning Speakers Committee (Box CSO1)
  - Mother Lists by Category (Box CSO1)
  - Motherhood/Feminist (Box CSO1)
  - Mothers' Custody Proposal, 1982 (Box CSO2)
  - Mother Interviewed re Brainwashing (Box CSO2)
  - Mother without Custody: Correspondence, 1981 (Box CSO2)
  - Ms. Foundation (Box CSO2)
  - NOW LDEP (Box CSO2)
  - NY NOW: Noreen Connell (Box CSO2)
  - Oct. 16 Meeting (Box CSO2)
  - Ongoing Funding (Box CSO2)
  - Organizations Upcoming Conferences (Box CSO2)
  - Panel Issues (Box CSO2)
  - P.E.N. Writers Fund (Box CSO2)
  - Personal/Formal Fundraising: In (Box CSO2)
  - Personal/Formal Fundraising: Out (Box CSO2)
  - Personal Fundraising Letters (Box CSO2)
  - Phyllis' Copy (Box CSO2)
  - Playboy - Fundraising (Box CSO2)
  - Press Release (Box CSO2)
  - Proposal for Speakout Funding, 1985 (Box CSO2)
  - Proposal Original. Taylor, 12/85 (Box CSO2)
  - Publicity for Speakout (Box CSO2)
  - Quotes: Early Writers (Box CSO2)
  - Quotes: General (Box CSO2)
  - Reference Articles (Box CSO2)
  - Resource List (Box CSO2)
  - Rockefeller Foundation (Box CSO2)
  - Rosenberg Foundation, 1983 (Box CSO2)
  - Search for Fundraising (Box CSO2)
  - Sept. 22, Moms Committed (Box CSO2)
  - Sept. 23: Miller/Chesler (Box CSO2)
  - Shainwald Benefit (Box CSO2)
  - Speakout Flyers (Box CSO2)
  - Speakout Lists Plus Video Legal (Box CSO2)
  - Speakout Mailing List (Box CSO2)
  - Speakout/Outreach (Box CSO2)
  - Speakout Planning Steps (Box CSO2)
  - Speakout Preliminary Budget (Box CSO2)
  - Speakers/Proposed: Battery and Custody (Box CSO2)
  - Speakers/Proposed: Career/Uppity Mothers (Box CSO2)
  - Speakers/Proposed: Children's Rights and Custody Panel (Box CSO2)
  - Speakers/Proposed: Foetal Politics and Custody Panel (Box CSO2)
  - Speakers/Proposed: General Custody Trends Panel (Box CSO2)
  - Speakers/Proposed: Incest/Battering and Custody Panel (Box CSO2)
  - Speakers/Proposed: Joint Custody/Fathers' Rights Panel (Box CSO2)
  - Speakers/Proposed: Judicial Reform and Custody Panel (Box CSO2)
  - Speakers/Proposed: Kidnapping and Custody Panel (Box CSO2)
  - Speakers/Proposed: Lesbian Mothers and Custody Panel (Box CSO2)
  - Speakers/Proposed: Mothers' Rights and Custody Panel (Box CSO2)
  - Speakers/Proposed: Non-Custodial (Forced) Panel (Box CSO2)
  - Speakers/Proposed: Non-Marital Heterosexuality (Box CSO2)
  - Speakers/Proposed: Poverty and Custody Panel (Box CSO2)
  - Speakers/Proposed: Race and Custody Panel (Box CSO2)
  - Speakers/Proposed: Stay at Home Mothers and Custody Panel (Box CSO2)
  - Speakers/Proposed: Unobligated Fathers and Custody Panel (Box CSO2)
  - Speakout Proposal (Box CSO2)
  - Sponsors (Box CSO2)
  - Steering Committee March and Expenses (Box CSO2)
  - Summer Stipends (Box CSO2)
  - Video Invite/Comments (Box CSO2)
  - Video Legal Matter (Box CSO2)
  - Video Project: Custody Speakout (Box CSO2)
  - Videos for Speakout (Box CSO2)
  - Volunteers (Box CSO2)
  - Volunteers: Outreach Films (Box CSO2)
  - Woods, Laurie (Box CSO2)
  - Letters to a Young Feminist subseries, 1990-1997and undated, bulk 1996-1997, 2 boxes
    The Letters to a Young Feminist subseries contains drafts, clippings, audiotapes, research, and notes related to Chesler's book, Letters to a Young Feminist, published in 1997. There is also material related to this project and an article Chesler wrote with the same title in the On the Issues series. See box OTI10.
    - Additional materials for book (Box W43)
    - Additional points (Box W43)
    - Advice, 1996 (Box W43)
    - BKSI-90 (Box W43)
    - Clippings, 1990-1996 (Box W43)
    - Clippings and notes, 1997 (Box W43)
    - Drafts and clippings (Box W43)
    - Editorial meetings/notes, 1996 (Box W43)
    - Four Walls manuscript, 1997 (Box W43)
    - Interviews with teens: Ely/Ann, 1996 (Box W43)
    - Legacy, 1996 (Box W44)
    - Letters to a Young Woman, with Solanus material (Box W44)
    - Literary quotes (Box W44)
    - Material used (Box W44)
    - Miscellaneous (Box W44)
    - OTI Column, 1996 (Box W44)
    - Outline, 1996 (Box W44)
    - Outlines, clippings, and notes, 1996 (Box W44)
    - Pages 33-64 (Box W44)
    - Previous drafts (Box W44)
    - Sanda Balaba letter, 1996 (Box W44)
    - Sanda questions, 1996 (Box W44)
    - Stats, 1996 (Box W44)
    - Young Feminists, 1996 (Box W44)
    - Interviews with teens, 1996 (Box W45)
      This box contains three audiocassette recordings of Chesler's interviews with teenagers. Tape labels read: Eli, Eva, and Ariel, 8/14/96; Jana, Dina, Coday, 8/15/96; and Ariel, Dan, and Josh.
- Women and Health Organizations Series, 1966-1975 and undated
  Clippings, flyers, newsletters, and other publicity about various mental health, feminist, and artistic organizations. Contains a small amount of correspondence. Arranged in alphabetical order using Chesler's original folder titles.
  - AAA Science (Box WHO1)
  - Abolition (American Association for Abolition of Involuntary Mental Hospitalization) (Box WHO1)
  - Abzug-Communicés (Box WHO1)
  - Advocates for the Arts (2 folders) (Box WHO1)
  - Amazon Media (Box WHO1)
  - American Association of University Professors (Box WHO1)
  - AAUP (Box WHO1)
  - Associate Council on the Arts (2 folders) (Box WHO1)
  - AFW (Association of Faculty Women) (Box WHO1)
  - AWP (Association of Women in Psychology) (Box WHO1)
  - Atlantis Study Journal (Box WHO1)
  - Attica/Harold (Box WHO1)
  - BARD (Box WHO1)
  - Barnard College, 1975 (Box WHO1)
  - Career Development Award (Box WHO1)
  - Center for the Study of Psychiatry (2 folders) (Box WHO1)
  - Circle of Support (Box WHO1)
  - City Woman (Box WHO1)
  - Collectives: New York City (Box WHO1)
  - Committee on Patients' Rights (Box WHO1)
  - Congressional Record (Box WHO1)
  - Council on National Literature Report (Box WHO1)
  - CUNY Women: CWC (CUNY Women's Coalition) (Box WHO1)
  - Daughters'-Women's Publisher (Box WHO1)
  - Ecumenical Women's Center (Box WHO1)
  - EDC News (Education Development Center) (Box WHO1)
  - Executive Woman (Box WHO1)
  - Feminist Press (Box WHO1)
  - Frontiers (Box WHO1)
  - Health Law Newsletter, 1972-1976, 3 folders (Box WHO1)
  - Hunger (Box WHO1)
  - Hypnosis (Box WHO1)
  - Insanity Defense (Box WHO1)
  - Institutional Abuse Psychosurgery (Box WHO1)
  - Institutional Legal Issues (Box WHO1)
  - Instructional Media, Inc. (Box WHO1)
  - International Biographical Center (Box WHO1)
  - Judicial/Mental (Box WHO1)
  - Know, Inc. (Box WHO1)
  - Laing, R.D. (Box WHO1)
  - Lawyers: Correspondence from and to (Box WHO1)
  - Leadership Questionnaire (Box WHO1)
  - Legal Issues (Box WHO1)
  - Legal Psychiatry (Box WHO1)
  - Legal Rights of Mental Patients (Box WHO1)
  - Legal Stuff/MPLP (Mental Patients' Liberation Project), LAMP (Legal Authority and Mental Patient Status); Lawyers/Briefs: John Matonis, Lew Louis (Box WHO1)
  - Lilith's Rib: Jewish Women for Affirmative Action (Box WHO1)
  - MacDowell Colony (Box WHO1)
  - Mental Care Asylums (Box WHO1)
  - Mental Health Court Digest, 1971-1974 (3 folders) (Box WHO1)
  - Mental Health Digest, MPLP, The Law Case (Box WHO1)
  - Mental Health Directory: New York (1966 and 1971) (Box WHO1)
  - Mental Hospitals (Box WHO1)
  - Mental Patients Liberation Project (Box WHO1)
  - Mental Patients' Rights: U.S. Backed (Box WHO1)
  - Mental Patients (Women) (Box WHO1)
  - NIMH (National Institute of Mental Health) (Box WHO1)
  - NOW Advisory Council (Box WHO1)
  - National Radical Feminist Conference Committee (Box WHO1)
  - National Women's Political Caucus (Box WHO1)
  - New Feminist Talent (Box WHO1)
  - New York State Education Department (Box WHO1)
  - Occult Phenomena (Box WHO1)
  - OWL (Older Women's Liberation) (Box WHO1)
  - P.E.N. American Center (2 folders) (Box WHO1)
  - PENN: Women for Equal Opportunity (University of Pennsylvania) (Box WHO1)
  - Psychiatric Imperialism (Box WHO1)
  - Psychological Studies at Richmond College (Box WHO1)
  - Quest: Feminist Quarterly (Box WHO1)
  - Radical Feminists (Box WHO1)
  - Radical Psychology, bibliography/outline (Box WHO1)
  - Rational Therapy (Box WHO1)
  - Redstockings (Box WHO1)
  - Sagaris: 1975sessions (Box WHO1)
  - SDS/NUC (Box WHO1)
  - Sex Roles -- Journal of Research (Box WHO1)
  - SIECUS (Sex Information and Education Council of the U.S.) (Box WHO1)
  - SIGNS: Journal of Women in Culture and Society (Box WHO1)
  - Strikes: Publishers England (Box WHO1)
  - SUNY Equal Opportunity (Box WHO1)
  - TELOS (Box WHO1)
  - Therapeutic Communities in America (Box WHO1)
  - Urban Study; Chapel Hill (Box WHO1)
  - West 13th Street Block Association (Box WHO2)
  - Warner Modular Publications (Box WHO2)
  - Warner Modular Stuff (Box WHO2)
  - Who's Who, Inc. (Box WHO2)
  - Woman's Way (Box WHO2)
  - Women's Action Alliance (4 folders) (Box WHO2)
  - Women's Energy Action Nucleus (Box WHO2)
  - Women's Equity Action League (Box WHO2)
  - Women's Forum (Box WHO2)
  - Women's Health Lobby (Box WHO2)
  - Women's History Research Collective -- Berkeley (Box WHO2)
  - Women in the News, Dec. 28, 1974 (Box WHO2)
  - Women's Studies Journal (Box WHO2)
  - Writers and Artists for peace in the Middle East (Box WHO2)
  - Writer's Colony: Yaddo (Box WHO2)
- Personal and Professional Papers Series
  - Teaching Material Subseries, 1968-1990 and undated
    The Teaching Material Subseries documents Phyllis Chesler's academic career and classroom teaching activities in various courses at City University of New York. The series includes her curriculum vitae, class lists and schedules, student evaluations, exams, and selected student papers for classes at the College of Staten Island and City University of New York. The series is arranged chronologically.
    - 1968, Course Materials: Counseling Center for Women (Box P/P1)
    - 1968-70, Selected Articles (Box P/P1)
    - 1969-72, Chesler (Box P/P1)
    - 1970-75, Media and Interviews (Box P/P1)
    - 1970-89, Selected Reviews of Chesler's Books (Box P/P1)
    - 1971-73, Selected Articles (Box P/P1)
    - 1972, Book Reviews: Women and Madness (Box P/P1)
    - 1973-1987, Evaluations and Recommendations (Box P/P1)
    - 1973, Chesler (Box P/P1)
    - 1974, Women's Counseling Class, Transcripts, (4 folders) (Box P/P1)
    - 1974, Women's Counseling Class (Box P/P1)
    - 1974, Transcripts and Classes (Box P/P1)
    - 1974-79, Chesler (Box P/P1)
    - 1976, Book Review: Women, Money and Power (Box P/P2)
    - 1976-7, Womanschool (Box P/P2)
    - 1976-9, Media and Interviews (Box P/P2)
    - 1976, Foreign Publishers (Box P/P2)
    - 1977-9, Selected Articles (Box P/P2)
    - 1978, Book Review: About Men (Box P/P2)
    - 1978, Comsearch Printouts (Box P/P2)
    - 1978, Overmannen, Synopsis (Box P/P2)
    - 1978, Curriculum Vitae in Progress (Box P/P2)
    - 1979, Book Review: With Child (Box P/P2)
    - 1979, (Fall), Intro to Psychology, Tues 4-5, Wed 4-4:50 (Box P/P2)
    - 1980, (Spring), Counseling, Psychology of Women (Box P/P2)
    - 1980, Grant Information (Box P/P2)
    - 1980 (Fall), Personality (Box P/P2)
    - 1980-2, Selected Articles (Box P/P2)
    - 1980-5, Media and Interviews (Box P/P2)
    - NY War Training Course (Box P/P2)
    - 1980, Chesler (Box P/P2)
    - 1982, Oct. 28, Curriculum Vitae (Box P/P2)
    - 1983-6, Selected Articles (Box P/P2)
    - 1984, Bart, Pauline B., et al, Attitudes Toward Pornography (Box P/P2)
    - 1984, Warnock (Box P/P2)
    - 1985-9, Surrogate, Canada (Box P/P2)
    - 1985, Surrogacy Arrangements Act (Box P/P2)
    - 1986, Computers in Sociological Work (Box P/P2)
    - 1986 (Fall), Ponch 100, Monday Evening (Box P/P2)
    - 1986 (Fall), COSI Correspondence (Box P/P2)
    - 1986 (Fall), 1986 COSI Courses (Box P/P2)
    - 1986 (Fall), Monday Morning 7:45-10:15 (Box P/P2)
    - 1986, (Spring) (Box P/P2)
    - 1986, Chesler (Box P/P2)
    - 1986, Media and Interviews (Box P/P2)
    - 1986 (Fall), Psych 100 Final Grades (Box P/P2)
    - 1986, Young Professionals Seminars (Box P/P2)
    - 1987, Committee of Promotion (Box P/P2)
    - 1987, Courses, Spring (Box P/P2)
    - 1987, Schedule, Spring (Box P/P2)
    - 1987-90, Peer Letter of Support (Promotion) (Box P/P2)
    - 1987-90, Selected Articles (Box P/P2)
    - 1987, Alejandra Munoz (Box P/P2)
    - 1987, Media and Interviews (Box P/P2)
    - 1987, Jan., Final Grades Psych 100 (Box P/P2)
    - 1987, Schedule of Classes (Box P/P3)
    - 1987, Chesler (Box P/P3)
    - 1988, Promotion Attempt (Box P/P3)
    - 1988, Chesler (Box P/P3)
    - 1988-9, Student Papers Evaluating Chesler's Class (Box P/P3)
    - 1988-9, Selected Student Letters for Professor Chesler (Box P/P3)
    - 1988, Book Review: Sacred Bond (Box P/P3)
    - 1988, Media/Interviews (Box P/P3)
    - 1989, Psychology of women, NYT (Box P/P3)
    - 1989 (Spring and Fall), Psychology of Women and Psychotherapy: 1 (Box P/P3)
    - 1989 (Spring and Fall), Psychology of Women and Psychotherapy: 2 (Box P/P3)
    - 1989 (Spring and Fall), Psychology of Women and Psychotherapy: 3 (Box P/P3)
    - 1989, Promotion Letters (Box P/P3)
    - 1989, Sept. 11, Selected Student Papers (Box P/P3)
    - 1989, Student Leaders and Papers (Box P/P3)
    - 1989, Publications and Interviews (Box P/P3)
    - 1989, Citations of Chesler's Work Not Covered by Computer Search (Box P/P3)
    - 1989, Computer Search of Academic Journals Citing Chesler's Work (Box P/P3)
    - 1989-1990, Selected Speeches (Box P/P3)
    - 1989, March -- 1990, August, Professional Activities (Box P/P3)
    - 1989, Media and Interviews (Box P/P3)
    - 1989 (Spring), Psychology of Women (Box P/P3)
    - 1989 (Fall), Student Evaluations, Chesler Classes (Box P/P3)
    - 1990, Curriculum Vitae (Box P/P3)
    - 1990, Recent Correspondence on Maintenance (Box P/P3)
    - 1990, Rebuttal/Chesler Evaluation (Box P/P3)
    - 1990, Media and Interviews (Box P/P3)
    - 1990, Interviews in Staten Island Advance (Box P/P3)
    - 1990, Vice President Barry Bressler (Box P/P3)
    - N.d., Psychology 100 Midterm Exam (Box P/P3)
    - N.d., Developmental Psychology, Tues. 6:25-9:00 (Box P/P3)
    - N.d., Bibliography A-M, undated (Box P/P3)
    - N.d., Bibliography N-Z, undated (Box P/P3)
    - N.d., Essays on Implementing Social Change, undated (Box P/P3)
  - Publicity Files subseries, ca. 1968-1985.
    The materials in the Publicity subseries, ca. 1968-1985, document efforts to publicize and promote Phyllis Chesler's writings. They include published interviews with and biographical pieces about Phyllis Chesler, articles about feminist issues quoting Chesler, and published excerpts from her work. The materials in this subseries are arranged alphabetically using Chesler's original folder titles.
    - List of Reviews and Articles (Box P/P4)
    - About Men (Box P/P4)
    - Avon Lawsuit: Women, Money and Power (Box P/P4)
    - Women, Money and Power (Box P/P4)
    - Journal of Marriage and the Family (Box P/P4)
    - Playgirl (Box P/P4)
    - Playgirl Article about Women (Box P/P4)
    - True Magazine (Box P/P4)
    - Clippings (Box P/P4)
    - Miscellaneous Publicity, 1970-1975 (Box P/P4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1980 Chatelaine Article (Box P/P4)
    - Miscellaneous Publicity (13 folders) (Box P/P4)
    - Miscellaneous Materials (Box P/P4)
    - Receipt Books (Box P/P4)
    - Requests for Science Article (Box P/P4)
    - Science "Maternal Influences on Learning" (Box P/P4)
  - Juvenilia subseries, ca. 1950-1959
    Artwork, writings, school work, and grade reports documenting Chesler's artistic and intellectual development through high school.
    - Miscellaneous artwork, writings, and school work (10 folders) (Box P/P5)
    - Oversize artwork and writings (Box P/P6 (oversize))
  - People Files subseries, ca. 1970-1989 (bulk 1970-1979)